hi everyone welcome my name is praveen
and we're here with the folks at a
circling Institute and you're here with
guys thanks Tom and Karina yeah and
we're gonna be diving into the advanced
art of circling course so this course
has been many years in the making we've
had interest from graduates of the
circlings to practitioner training for
many years going back before that to CC
LTE and even before that to other
courses you might have been a graduate
of t3 and integral or taking out a
circling related courses and we really
kind of got together to design something
that we think is a great fit for people
who want to take their circling skills
facilitation and how they show up in
circles to the next level so let's start
it off guide you want to share a little
something about this course and what has
you excited and what you imagine people
experience yeah I think the thing I'm
mostly excited is is this Noah and all
the people who have taken AOC and and
the what what gets awakened in them
through taking it in the various
interests of all the things that are
available encircling that come up that
if you're not educated around them you
won't be able to see them and so I'm
excited about that that your own
personal development and the deepening
of the your the education of your
listening and you're seeing so that when
you look at a circle you see so much
more and I'm super excited to watch that
happen yeah I was talking to another one
of our core faculty members guy and I
was telling them how an artist circling
you become like proficient and circling
like you graduate and you are a
practitioner of circling and like for me
advanced practitioner training it's kind
of like circling Graduate School where
you go from being a proficient
practitioner or like a member of the
chorus line to being an artist or a
soloist encircling so I think that's the
thing I'm most excited about in
designing and teaching the course is
that we're taking people who already
have the core foundation of circling
skills and helping them find their
unique voice
and find the way that their own you know
worldview and their perspective and any
strengths and tools that they have from
other trainings can now be layered on
top of the fundamentals circling skills
to bring their own particular grand and
approach to circling to the next level
and to really ground their confidence
and their experience so that they can
know just more fully shine in the world
yeah I love that you're sharing that
kinda that makes a lot of sense in
particular I think well we've been
hearing for people who come out of
circling it's like okay I think I got
the skills I got the steps I got the
model I'll keep practicing it what else
what else do you notice and often what
we find is to talk about what else we
notice you actually need to go into
quite a bit more framework and practice
and background because there's all kinds
of ways people are showing up in circles
in subtle ways in which they're actually
for example creating secure attachment
or breaking secure attachment there's
ways in which they're not acknowledging
the shadow what's happening the circle
or even within themselves and there's
ways in which there's meta-level stuff
happening the circle not just the tone
or whether people feel safe or trusting
but like much deeper levels that we can
start to unpack that are happening in a
group dynamic level in a circle
especially if a group of people meet
continuously over time I start to become
a team what's happening in the arc and
narrative the team and you've seen this
and are circling trainings as well - as
a team progresses and all of those are
the kinds of stuff that kind of brings
it more into a Jedi level of circling
awareness like the idea of like you ever
listen to especially classical musicians
and they're playing a piece and they've
hit all the right notes and you you know
that they're you know unaccomplished
violinist but it doesn't move you like
you're not moved by the piece and like
for me that's art of circling one when
people come out of it it's like oh I you
know I know how to play this piece but
I'm not necessarily gonna move some of
the tears with it and with the
individual attention and the deeper dive
we can give them it the advanced
practitioner they'll really embody their
circling in
way that you know like like yo yo mas
cello can move you to tears even when
he's playing the same concerto that
someone who's technically proficient
played and had no impact on you or
little impact on you I think that that's
the piece that gets me most excited
about working with the students who will
sign up for the Advanced Course it's
like we get to take them who are already
accomplished artists and really help
them become exquisite and extraordinary
just one more thing apart a part of that
I love what you just said I'm really
excited to about you know in the it'll
it'll progress towards things but
through throughout we're gonna be
looking a lot at not just circling the
person and their personality and and all
the stuff that you know you're someone
but we're gonna we're gonna circle the
structure of itself right like get it
like a deeper the deeper levels of being
and ontology and to be able oh one just
to be able to see that like just to be
able to look at somebody and see that
they have a cell and it has the
structure and that to be able to like
through language and through the way
that you're being is actually circle the
deeper structure so it goes much deeper
than a lot like most of the circles go
and so I'm excited just to share a lot
of the non-dual stuff that I've just
been experiencing doing courses and
stuff that happened spontaneously and
like bring them together and start to
teach it again so it's actually teach
that I'm stoked about that yeah we're a
OC is kind of interpersonal and this
course we're gonna do a lot of the
intrapersonal will do the interpersonal
and then we're gonna go transpersonal on
you it's gonna be hot yeah yeah and the
other part too is to you know do C
course or the equivalent course if
you're coming from other circling
trainings is really a foundation for
this because he those foundations are
not there then this stuff this stuff
will be helpful but the basic things
about getting someone's world really
helping them go to deep places that's
gotta still be there so it's gonna
really build upon that and one of the
things that we're gonna do to really
build upon it is we're gonna really
separate out
some of the teaching pieces from the
practice pieces so in a moment we're
gonna show you what the course looks
like we're gonna go into the course page
briefly just to touch on that but one
thing that we're really emphasizing here
is when you come to the live weekends
we've already kind of covered the
groundwork material on you the schema of
what's happening the background there
reading the framework the understandings
all the stuff that's absorbed in terms
of understanding some of that legwork
has already been done so when you show
up we can really dive into an
experiential full-on and this definitely
is an advanced course so there's gonna
be some hand-holding but we're also
gonna kind of throw in some deep waters
and and watch what unfolds and we're
gonna dive in ourselves too as
facilitators like we're not just here
completely to just step into the
facilitator role and teach like we're
gonna be fallible ourselves to be
getting venerable ourselves and we're
gonna play with you and this as well to
really set the tone for what's possible
it's now a good time to tell them kind
of pragmatic stuff the structure of the
course and yeah let me go ahead and
share my screen I'll pull up okay so
while you're finding that guy probably
we can just say there's four main
modules but in addition to the four main
modules guy will be doing bimonthly sot
songs where he does more kind of
meditative practice groups and
experiential practice groups you'll be
put into peer practice groups as well so
that you can circle and practice skills
with each other and all of the advanced
students will be invited if they'd like
to join us on the webinars for the aoc
foundational course and you can coach
circles if you'd like to get practice
coaching other circulars that's a little
perk that we're adding for all of you
who are gonna be joining this course you
know we'll have the private Facebook
group and one like Praveen said we'll
have the you know readings and
supplemental material and homework
assigned
it's for you to do before you get to
your three-day weekends so that when we
get to the three-day weekends it's all
practice process question-and-answer
practice some more you know process some
more some more QAS
and we'll really be fully immersed in
the material but a lot of juicy learning
in okay I'm going to go ahead and share
my screen and here we go and so if you
look so we can see the first three
weekends here you want to like walk us
through the basics of this Karenna just
what we're expecting in the weekends and
this is all available on the circling
Institute page under programs
it's the advanced practitioner program
and so as we said there's four three day
weekend modules pretty much over a six
month period we're gonna start in June
in June we do weekend one which is
establishing home base and we're gonna
cover secure attachment and symptomatic
inclusion in your circles and as you can
see there so we'll talk about how you
set and hold a container and how you
kind of manage the group so that people
are feeling included and safe and open
enough to be vulnerable we'll go over
some tools for creating that secure
attachments in a circle and tips for
avoiding things that might threaten it
um and you'll hear us say often and
circling like the deeper you are
connected to yourself the more deeply
you can connect to others and that's
we're going to talk about when that last
bullet point when it says using self as
an instrument you know really kind of
fully knowing yourself and who you are
so that you can notice when you're being
impacted by different members of the
circle and that you can use that impact
as data for a richer circle as opposed
to kind of getting distracted by it or
needing to you know work around it or
avoid it
anything either you add there I think
one thing I'll add is with secure
attachment there's tons to work on and
tons to share and one of the things
we're gonna do is just keep it in some
ways it's the little subtle things are
happening somatically and energetically
they make all the difference so we're
gonna really kind of dive into those
things like do these three key things
and really kind of get practical about
it to who are the ways in which you're
breaking that attachment with little
subtle behavioral shifts yes subtle but
powerful so you don't have to become a
master at attachment theory and a lot of
it like you said prob is somatic like
just when you notice that you're not
feeling so connected or the group is not
feeling so connected and what are some
simple things that you can do to
restructure that yeah and this is really
good this will be really good if in your
earn a relationship or gonna be in one
like being able to identify those
patterns and like understand it and
share it it's a huge difference
beautiful yeah let's go on to the second
weekend which is once we got a home base
establish we can start to enter murkier
more dangerous water access we should
say did someone else want to take this
one or you want me to just run through
once you go ahead start it out yeah
great so yeah so then once we once we
talked about home base and talked about
shadow and transference and protections
in that in the second module I think
this is my favorite module and so and
this one will actually be that your
homework in between these two modules
will be to work on kind of identifying
some of your own shadow aspects and
recognizing how do they show up you know
how do they show up in circles when
you're being circled how do they show up
as a facilitator in what you attend to
or avoid how do they show up in your
relationships in general and there's
even gonna be a little homework for you
to actually interview significant people
in your life and get their feedback on
what they think you know your shadow
work might be and in the
for those of you who are taking this
course because you want to become better
facilitators this is where we're gonna
address objections and transference and
how you manage that with grace and ease
hopefully in your circles yeah and part
of that process isn't just like okay let
me just accept that and go back to
circling it's like how do you actually
welcome it integrate it don't even own
what's really there because otherwise it
goes back into shadow again and how do
you do it from a seat of power where
you're not collapsing under someone's
projection but you're but you're not
resisting it either and like how do you
find that sweet spot where you can
actually try on someone's project
someone's projection and integrate it
and kind of honor it in a way that still
has you in the seat of power and
facilitation and I'll just say is if you
could just imagine think about all that
all your inner demons that torture you
we all have them right imagine if there
was a way to integrate them such that
those the power of those inner demons
were on your side that's the whole point
is it enormous of power and shadow but
it's disowned so it's like just imagine
if all your neurosis is and all the
parts of yourselves like God on your own
side and got behind your own goals
that's that's the power of it personally
that's it yeah one thing that's it and
then one thing about that too I think
particularly I think where I'm excited
about this is often what can happen at
the end of a circling training is people
step into certain role okay I'm a
circular and this is how circulars are
and let me go put on my circular hat and
then what happens is all these other
parts of ourselves the part that maybe
isn't that relational of hearts may be
angry and pissed off how can all of
those parts be integrated and how we
show up and so this is the area where we
really dive in with each of you I start
to work with you so all of those parts
now are welcome
and so when you circle you're bringing
your full self to the circle cool yeah
alright the next part we've the
collective I'll share a little something
about this and then I have both of you
jump in so one of the things that often
happens so there's what
in a circle there's a process of the
circling in the artist circling often we
tend to bias towards simpler being a
strong facilitator and knowing what to
do how to hold the group what to do what
the next step is and that's an important
development stage to becoming a skill
circular so you're not just sort of
passively allowing whatever is happening
and not actually being in some ways
conducting what's going on and then
there's a deeper cut of how you conduct
stuff where you actually start to have
an understanding on a systems level like
what the groups tend to be like what are
the stages in which groups tend to go to
what is it like in a storming stage of a
group and there's conflicts and tensions
what kind of archetypes come off and
what we found consistently over and over
is that they're gonna be people who are
gonna be critical they're gonna be
people who are pissed off at me people
who are gonna be caretaking all these
sort of certain I'm naming a couple
examples archetypes that you show up
over and over again the group and if you
just kind of diminish that or you take
that person out someone else will have
to play that role it's almost like
groups of a certain energy that comes in
and so think of it almost like as a
symphony and so what is it like as a
circular to not just expect it but to
embrace it and to see all of those as
actually resources and tools for how
systems work as a collective and then
start to marshal that as a conductor and
welcome it beautiful this is word all
the wild stuff comes out yeah and then
we add a little piece here this is the
stuff where we sort of step away from
circling through me I'm facilitating and
we're going to circle and if it's a
birthday circle as we call it - circling
through us and really sort of listening
deeper and what's happening in the field
and having a much deeper field awareness
a little teaser taster for the lead-in
to weekend for yeah take we'll take our
first foray into the transpersonal
approaches circling the weekend for is
also going to be you know where we fill
in any of the gaps and you really ground
your practice you have here your
opportunity to you know ask questions or
you know get feedback on your unique
style of circling and integrate
everything that we've learned over the
past
for months but there you know in
addition to the transpersonal yeah yeah
guy do you want to share a little bit
about what the so the transpersonal is a
shift in orientation before that is
still happening to a large degree in a
personal level like how do I make groups
feel safe
what kind of what kind of stuff is in a
shadow let's bring it out now what's
happening with the group field between
all of us and then the transpersonal is
where that goes one tier higher even and
the orientation shifts really and so
good I do want to say a little something
about that think about it it's like this
is where we're really like were in a
certain sense we're circling being right
so it's like you know you if you if you
look at it like this if you I can't
think of a bigger category than being so
like my understanding or my relationship
to being since all that all my other
categories everything else that I know
and called my life happened inside of
that category if I make a shift in
meaning that's a shift in everything but
I would say that like being or the sense
of the whole is very difficult to see
and it takes a different it makes
different eyes like a keeper eyes and it
takes a different logic to get
accustomed to what is most close to us
but the most concealed and and there's
an artfulness to it and I think by the
time that we get here we're gonna be
able to are it'll already be happening
and we can just point to it more so what
that may look like is like some some
like lots of fun deep inquiry exercises
but also like really being comfortable
with going to a space of the unknown
with somebody and finding out what
happens and getting a sense of the
greater whole of it and being able to
relate to it in an intimate way I'm
stoked about that
yeah so a mine I think you're absolutely
right guy by the time that we complete
the third module I think people will
already be like instinctively doing it
and then once they come for weekend for
its
more just about making the distinctions
and I'm helping them do it more
intentionally as opposed to it being the
water they're swimming in I would say
the personal takeaway of this is that
you know this is really one of those
things that you could only it's like
wait at that level in order it's almost
like being get only see be right on a
certain level so it's like this is where
it's you really get the sense of that
two circle is the circle with your whole
being it's not a requirement or an a nod
but it's a total it's it's it's
reflecting the whole through yourself
and in a real deep shift and
understanding who you are this is where
this is this is the good part
yeah yeah great all right well I think
we've covered the basics here so if
you've seen this and if you're
interested definitely go ahead and reach
out feel free to shoot us an email reach
out to us by circling Institute or
through our personal contacts any form
works and if you're thinking about
signing up the registration is active
and it's live we have full registration
prices or early bird happening you'll
save five hundred five hundred dollars
so we're giving a big discount there if
you signed up by April 1st so before
April Fool's Day and we've had a lot of
interest from people
pretty much everyone we've talked to
about it you know going back to a OC as
well as previous courses your long
circling courses has been extremely
interested in waiting for a course like
this in a lot of ways this is a course
that we we wish we had when we went to
be circling training both me and Carina
and others and I think in some ways is
the course the guys are waiting to teach
once the bandwidth has opened up so
we're excited about this I'm you expect
a lot of graduates are going to be
interested and they're capping it and
it's a number to keep it intimate just
given the instructor student ratio and
because it's the first year we're
running it so we expect it will fill out
from the interest that we've had and if
you think you're ready for it or if
you're not sure either way reach out and
we can
a conversation with you about it and
we're really excited looking forward to
making this happen come summer I love
that you would be a little cryptic about
we will cap it at a certain amount of
student yeah we and like he said we want
to be able to give you the personal more
personal attention and that's why we're
gonna keep this class much smaller than
the level one art of circling courses so
that you can get that more personal
experience the more personal attention
and the deeper richer experience you
know like we said it's circling graduate
school yeah all right well thanks
everyone thanks for listening look
forward to hearing from you and thanks
guy thanks Carina excited about what's
unfolding here